A Guide to the John Z. Bowers papers FA1415
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Western Medicine in Japan, 2.46 Cubic Feet
  - Rangaku - Yamawaki Toyo, G. Achiwa (Box 5, Folder 149)
    "On the First Anatomical Chart in Japan" by Goro Achiwa
  - Rangaku - Translations from Nihon Ishigaku Zasshi (Box 5, Folder 150)
    "On the Bansho-Shirabesho" by Jiro Numata; "Japanese Medicine before and after Meiji Restoration - on Oyatoi Gaijin (Hired Foreigners)" by Taizo Ogawa
  - Rangaku - Japanese Medical Schools, 1752-1850, Ogata and Shosendo (Box 5, Folder 151)
    Notes and Translations
  - Rangaku - Sugita Gempaku (Box 5, Folder 152)
    Notecard
  - Rangaku - Otsuki Gentaku - Chronology (Keio-Otori) (Box 5, Folder 153)
    "Chronology of Otsuki Gentaku"; Notes; "Acceptance of Western Cultures in Japan from the Sixteenth to the Nineteenth Century" by Ranzaburō Ōtori
  - Rangaku - Reprint from Ogawa Teizo Showing Oranda Shogatsu (Box 5, Folder 154)
    Reprint
  - Rangaku - Rangaku Kaitei (Box 5, Folder 155)
    Keio-Otori
  - Rangaku - References (Box 5, Folder 156)
  - Rangaku - Oranda Shogatsu (Box 5, Folder 157)
    "From the Hstiroy of Japanese Medicine, V. People at the Party in Oranda-shōgatsu" by Ogawa Teizo (translation); Reprint
  - Rangaku - "Otsuki Gentaku and the Spread of 'Rangaku'," Chapter XI (Box 5, Folder 158)
  - Rangaku - Otsuki Gantaku - Rangaku (Box 5, Folder 159)
    Correspondence, Translations; "Occasional Papers, Center for Japanese Studies, No. 3"
  - Rangaku - "Report on Medical Education in Japan" by Richard M. Pearce, 1921 (Box 6, Folder 160)
- Medicine Around the World, 2.37 Cubic Feet
  This series contains research and reference materials related to Bowers' writings on Medicine Around the World. Files include reprints, articles, notes, and translations.
  - Portugal - Todos-os-Santos (Box 6, Folder 161)
    Andanças do ensino medico na capital: Do Hospital Real de Todos-os-Santos ao Hospital de Santa Maria by S. da Costa Scadura and J.T. Montalvão Machado
  - Portugal - "Tomotercero Honor del Gran Patriarca San Ignacio de Loyola" (Box 6, Folder 162)
    Photocopies; Translation
  - Portugal - "The Dominican Mission in Japan (1602-1622) and Lope De Vega" by C.R. Boxer and J.S. Cummins (Box 6, Folder 163)
  - Portugal - Portuguese Medicine (Box 6, Folder 164)
    "Onward and Upward with Technology: Giving Up the Gun"; Postcards; "A História da Medicina no Ensino Médico-cirúgico de Lisboa" by M.B. Barbosa Sueiro"; "Alguém! Dr. Artur Manuel Vianna Fernandes (1903-1964)" by M.B. Barbosa Sueiro; "O Grande Historiador da Mdicina Professor Maximiano Lemos" by M.B. Barbosa Sueiro; "Origens do Ensino da Anatomia Humana Médico-Cirúgica" by M.B. Barbosa Sueiro; "Súmula Histórica da Medicina Escolar" by M.B. Barbosa Sueiro; "Súmula da Vida Interlope de Alonso Rodriguez de Guevara" by M.B. Barbosa Sueiro; "A 'Comissão Geológica de Portugal' e o 'IX Congresso Internacional de Antropologia e de Arqueologia Prehistóricas'" by M.B. Barbosa Sueiro; "O Professor José António Serrano: Homem de Pensamento, de Cultura e de Acção" by M.B. Barbosa Sueiro; "Luís Pasteur: Uma Vida de Labor e de Glória" by M.B Barbosa Sueiro; "Jubilação do Professor Doutor Vítor Fontes" by M.B. Barbosa Sueiro; "The Indiana University Bookman, No. 11" (1973)
  - Portugal - "Das Schulwesen der Jesuiten in Japan" by K. Schilling (Box 6, Folder 165)
    Translation; "Das Ärztliche Institut in Ōita" (book chapter)
  - Portugal - "The Beginning of the School of Surgery of the Royal All Saints Hospital (1504-65)" by Costa Santos (Box 6, Folder 166)
    Translation; "O início da Escola de Cirugia do Hospital Real de Todos os Santos, 1504-1565"
  - Portugal - Schilling - Franciscan Hospitals in Myako (Box 7, Folder 167)
    Translations; Chapters, "Neue Zeitschrift für Missionswissenschaft"
  - Portugal - "Historia de las Missiones" (Box 7, Folder 168)
  - Portugal - "The Paradox of 'The Treasury of Medicines' by Gregorio Lopez (1542-1596)" by Francisco Guerra (Box 7, Folder 169)
  - Portugal - "Macao as a Religious and Commercial Entrepôt in the 16th and 17th Centuries" by C.R. Boxer (Box 7, Folder 170)
  - Portugal - "Francisco Vieira de Figueiredo: A Portuguese Merchant-Adventurer in South East Asia, 1624-1667" by C.R. Boxer (Box 7, Folder 171)
  - Portugal - "Two Pioneers of Tropical Medicine: Garcia d'Orta and Nicolás Monardes" by C.R. Boxer (Box 7, Folder 172)
  - Portugal - "Plain Sailing" (Box 7, Folder 173)
  - Portugal - Macao - Block Print (Box 7, Folder 174)
  - Portugal - "The Practice of Indian Medicine in Goa during the Portuguese Rule, 1510-1699" by João Manuel Pacheco de Figueiredo (Box 7, Folder 175)
  - Portugal - The Portuguese Period (Box 7, Folder 176)
    Correspondence; "Garcia da Orta: Pioneer in Medicine and Botany" by Louis Pelner; "Drugs from the Indies and t he Political Economy of the Sixteenth Century" by Francisco Guerra; "Europe's Side-Door to China" by Mike Banks
  - Portugal - Luis de Almeida (Box 7, Folder 177)
    Correspondence; "Luis de Almeida: Chirurgien et Marchand, Avant son Entrée dans la Compagnie de Jésus au Japon, 1525(?)-1556"; Translations
  - Portugal - "Manoel Coelho de Sampayo" (Box 7, Folder 178)
  - Portugal - Lisbon (Box 7, Folder 179)
    Brochure
  - Portugal - U.S. Botany (Box 7, Folder 180)
    Review, "The Evolution of Biology"; "French Naturalists in the Mississippi Valley" by Joseph Ewan; "Makers of North American Botany" by Joseph Ewan; "John Bachman and the Happoldt European Journal" by Joseph Ewan
  - Portugal - "The Letter that Changed History" Clipping (Box 7, Folder 181)
  - Portugal - National Archives, Researcher Information (Box 7, Folder 182)
  - Portugal - Friedlander (Box 7, Folder 183)
    "Mark Twain, Social Critic, and His Image of the Doctor" by Walter J. Friedlander; "Louis Pasteur and His Stroke: A Lesson in Perserverance" by Walter J. Friedlander; "About Three Old Men: An Inquiry into How Cerebral Arteriosclerosis has Altered World Politics" by Walter J. Friedlander
  - Portugal - Draft (Partial) (Box 7, Folder 184)
  - Portugal - C.R. Boxer (Box 7, Folder 185)
    "The Dutch East-Indiamen: Their Sailors, Their Navigators, and Life on Board, 1602-1795" by C.R. Boxer; "Einige Aspekte der westlichen Geschichtsschreibung über den fernen Osten, 1500-1800" by C.R. Boxer; F. Guerra (translation?); "Epítome de História da Medicina Portuguesa
  - Africa - "World Health", 1970 May (Box 7, Folder 186)
  - Africa, "L'Ensignement de la Medicine en Afrique Francophone et a Madagascar" by P. Pene (Box 7, Folder 187)
  - Arab/Islam - Arab Medicine (Box 7, Folder 188)
  - Arab/Islam - Rhazes-Avicenna (Box 7, Folder 189)
  - Arab/Islam - Byzantine Botany (Box 7, Folder 190)
    "Byzantine Botanical Lexicography" by Jerry Stannard
  - Arab/Islam - "The Origin and Development of Greco-Egyptian Alchemy" by William Jerome Wilson, 1941 (Box 7, Folder 191)
  - Arab/Islam - "The Arab Medical Organization in Nineteenth Century Tunisia" by N.E. Gallagher, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 192)
  - Asia - South-East, excluding Japan - Food-Chinese (Box 7, Folder 193)
    Artcile, "The Sweet and the Sour" by Mark Elvin
  - Asia - South-East, excluding Japan - Thailand (Box 7, Folder 194)
    "Material on 19th Century Thailand at the Toyo Bunko, Tokyo" by Kenjiro Ichikawa; "The Social Organization and Ecology of Medical Practice in Taiwan" by Paul U. Unschuld
  - Asia - South-East, excluding Japan - The Asia Foundation (Box 7, Folder 195)
    "The Avery Brundage Collection of Asian Art"
  - Caribbean - Caribbean History (Box 7, Folder 196)
    "The Influence of Disease on Race, Logistics, and Colonization in the Antilles" by Francisco Guerra
  - Caribbean - Unfoldered Materials (Box 8, Folder 197)
    "Robespierre Under Scrutiny" by Alden Whitman; "Africa and the Caribbean in the Atlantic Slave Trade" by Richard B. Sheridan; "Mortality and the Medical Treatment of Slaves in the British West Indies" by Richard B. Sheridan; "Obeah is a Fact of Life, and Afterlife, in the Caribbean"
  - France - Unfoldered Materials (Box 8, Folder 198)
    "The History of the Publication of Bernard of Gordon's Liber de Conservatione Vitae Humanae" by Ynez Violé O'Neill; "Dates in the Printed Editions of the Lilium Medicinae" by Ynez O'Neill; "L'approche sanitaire française, I and II" by P. Pene, J. Brunet-Jailly and J. Delmon; Grant Application, Louis S. Greenbaum, "Jacques Tenon and Hospital Reform in 18 C. France"
  - France - L. Pasteur (Box 8, Folder 199)
    "Louis Pasteur Sesquicentennial (1822-1972)" by J.R. Porter
  - France - R. Descartes (Box 8, Folder 200)
    "Descartes' Physiological Method: Position, Principles, Examples" by Thomas S. Hall; "Microbiomechanics, Rene Descartes (1596-1650)"; "A New View of Neurology's Debt to Descartes" by T.S. Hall; "Rene Descartes (Renatus Cartesius), Philosopher, Mathematician, and Physiologist"
  - France - Daniel Bargeton - Papers - Photographs (Box 8, Folder 201)
    "Situation a la Faculte Centrale"; "Projet de Sectorissation de la Faculte Centrale"; "Enseignement Intefre - Enseignement Compact"; "Scheme General de l'Engeignement des Sciences Fondamontales non Integrees"; "Projet d'Enseignement de la Physiologie a la Faculte Centrale"; "Formation Ingenieur et Formation Contre-Maitre"; Sciences Fondamentales Avant - Clinique - Apres"; "Orientation Selective"
  - France - F. Vicq d'Azyr (Box 8, Folder 202)
    Photocopies
  - France - European Medicine - Grmek (Box 8, Folder 203)
    "Nobody Called It the Schmidt" by William A. Krauss; "L'Œvre de Charles Estienne et l'École Antatomique Parisienne" by Pierre Huard and Mirko Drazen Grmek; "Ancient Slavic Medicine" by Mirko Drazen Grmek; "Collection de Planches Anatomiques du XVIIe Siècle Peintes sur Soie"; "Leçons sur le Diabète" by Claude Bernard; "First Steps in Claude Bernard's Discovery of the Glycogenic Function of the Liver" by M.D. Grmek
  - Germany - Dieter Jetter (Box 8, Folder 204)
    "The Medical World of Frederick the Great" by Ilza Veith; "Zur Geschichte der Medizin in Stuttgart" by Dieter Jetter
  - Germany - Medical Education in Germany (Box 8, Folder 205)
    Notes; "Die Empfehlungen des Wissenschaftsrates zur Neuordnung des medizinischen Studiums" by Ernst Schütte (and translation); "Enschreibungsbeschränkungen bei der Medizinischen Fakultät der Universität München für das Studium der Medizin" (and translation)
  - Germany - Unfoldered materials (Box 8, Folder 206)
    "The Historical Development of Experimental Anaphylaxis" by H. Schadewaldt; "MD, April 1977"; "Zur Geschichte des Fermentbegriffes" by H. Schadewaldt"
  - Great Britain - Leprosy (Box 8, Folder 207)
    "Medieval 'Leprosy' in the British Isles" by William MacArthur
  - Great Britain - Guy Thomas (Box 8, Folder 208)
    Correspondence; "Thomas Guy: A Short Biography" by I.H. Dodd
  - Great Britain - Students in Osler House Garden Image (Box 8, Folder 209)
  - Great Britain - Jos. Lister (Box 8, Folder 210)
    "Lister, His Books, and Evolvement of His Antiseptic Wound Practices" by Owen H. Wangensteen and Sarah D. Wangensteen
  - Great Britain - English Universities (Box 8, Folder 211)
    "Medical Education in Great Britain and Ireland, 1858-1967" by Lord Cohen of Birkenhead; "The Lady of Letters in the Eighteenth Century" by Irvin Ehrenpreis and Robert Halsband; "The Universities and Science in Seventeenth Century England" by Barbara Shapiro; "Science, Medicine, and the Universities of Early Modern England: Background and Sources, Part 2" by Robert G. Frank, Jr.
  - Great Britain - Liverpool (Box 8, Folder 212)
    "Sydenham's Influence Abroad" by F.N.L. Poynter; "The Liverpool Medical School and its Physicians (1642-1934)" by Lord Cohen of Birkenhead; "History of the Liverpool School of Tropical Medicine" by B.G. Maegraith
  - Great Britain - Renaissance Medicine (Box 8, Folder 213)
  - Great Britain - "The Medical School of the Royal College of Surgeons in Ireland: A Cost-Benefit Study", 1971 (Box 8, Folder 214)
  - Great Britain - Keats Memorial Lectures, Lord Evans of Hungershall (Box 8, Folder 215)
  - Great Britain - Spread of Western Medicine, George Basalla (Box 8, Folder 216)
    Notecards
  - Great Britain - "Thomas Willis as a Physician" by Kenneth Dewhurst (Box 8, Folder 217)
  - Great Britain - Wellcome Calendar, 1888 (Box 8, Folder 218)
  - Great Britain - Jarcho, Forbes (Box 8, Folder 219)
    "Mortality Books for 1820 to 1849 from the Parish of St. Bride, Fleet Street, London" by Thomas R. Forbes; "Verbal Charms in British Folk Medicine" by Thomas R. Forbes; "The Regulation of English Midwives in the Eighteenth and Nineteenth Centuries" by Thomas R. Forbes; "Mortality Books for 1774-1793 and 1833-1835 from the Parish of St. Giles, Cripplegate, London" by Thomas R. Forbes; "On the Motion of Blood in the Veins" by Lord Cohen of Birkenhead; "The Right Honorable Sir Thomas Clifford Allbutt F.R.S. (1836-1925)" by Lord Cohen of Birkenhead; "The Chelsea Physic Garden" by Saul Jarcho
  - Great Britain - "450 Years Old - What of the Future?" by Max Rosenheim (Box 8, Folder 220)
  - Great Britain - National Health Service (Box 8, Folder 221)
    "The National Health Service of Great Britain" by Willard C. Rappleye
  - Great Britain - Scotland (Box 9, Folder 222)
    "Scottish Medical Education" by L.R.C. Agnew
  - Great Britain - Medical Education in Britain, 1966 (Box 9, Folder 223)
    "Draft Recommendations as to Basic Medical Education"
  - Great Britain - English Medicine (Box 9, Folder 224)
    "The Voyage of Surgery" by J. Needham; "A Short History of Gonville and Caius College Chapel"; "Bonville and Caius College"
  - Great Britain - "The Antipodes: Private Practice Publicly Supported" by Theodore Fox (Box 9, Folder 225)
  - Great Britain - "Bluttransfusion im 17, Jahrhundert" by Alistair Cameron Crombie (Box 9, Folder 226)
  - Great Britain - "Chaucer and Medicine" by Ynez Violé O'Neill (Box 9, Folder 227)
  - Great Britain - "Helkiah Crooke, M.D., F.R.C.P., 1576-1648" by C.D. O'Malley (Box 9, Folder 228)
  - Greece - Ancient Medicine (Box 9, Folder 229)
  - Greece - Galen (Box 9, Folder 230)
    "Another Look at the 'Anatomia Porci'" by Ynez Violé O'Neill
  - Greece - Greek and Roman (Box 9, Folder 231)
    "Helth Care Delivery Systems in Ancient Greece and Rome" by Warren L. Kump; "On Medical Education in Greece and Rome" by I.E. Drabkin; Notes
  - Greece - "Hippocrates of Ostia" by Dickinson W. Richards (Box 9, Folder 232)
  - Greece - "Max Leonard Rosenheim, Baron Rosenheim of Camden, 1908-1972" by George Pickering (Box 9, Folder 233)
  - Sir Hans Sloane - Biographical (Box 9, Folder 234)
    "Sir Hans Sloane: Naturalist, Physician, Collector, and Benefator" by Burton Chance; "Some Aspects of the Life and Times of Sir Hans Sloane" by W.W.D. Thomson; "Sir Hans Sloane" by Byers
  - Sir Hans Sloane - Eye Medicine (Box 9, Folder 235)
    "Sir Hans Sloane's Account for an Efficacious Medicine for Soreness of the Eyes: An Episode in Eighteenth Century Ophthalmology" by Burton Chance
  - Sir Hans Sloane - Will (Box 9, Folder 236)
    "Authentic Copies of the Codicils Belonging to the last Will and Testament of Sir Hans Sloane, Bart., deceased, which relate to his collection of books and curiosities"
  - Sir Hans Sloane - Sloane and Newton (Box 9, Folder 237)
    "Isaac Newton, Hans Sloane, and the Académie Royale des Sciences" by Bernard Cohen
  - India - "Physical Medicine and Rehabilitation in Ancient India" by N.H. Keswani (Box 9, Folder 238)
  - India - Basham - Indian Contributions (Box 9, Folder 239)
  - India - Leslie - Ayurvedic Medicine (Box 9, Folder 240)
    "The Professionalizing Ideology of Medical Revivalism" by Charles Leslie; "Ayurvedic Medicine" by Pepita Fairfax
  - India - History of Medicine (Box 9, Folder 241)
    "Ancient Hindu Orthopaedic Surgery" by N.H. Keswami; "Indian Journal of Orthopaedics, Vol. 1, No. 2 and 3, cover picture descriptions"; "Exhibition of the History of Indian Medicine and Its Spread in Asia"; "Research in Some of the Concepts of Ayurveda and the Application of Modern Chemistry and Experimental Pharmacology Therefor" by C. Dwarakanath and G.V. Satyavati; "Experimental Studies on the Hypocholesterolemic Effect of 'Commiphoroa mukul.' Engl. (GUGGUL)." by G.V. Satyavati, C. Dwarakanath, and S.N. Tripathi; "Research on Indian Medicinal Plants"; Notes (on Ayurvedic Medicine); "Pediatric Education and Research" by P.N. Wahi; "Modern India's Ancient Medicine" by Charles Leslie; "Modern Medicine in India Traditional Setting - A New Brew in an Old Vati" by N.H. Keswani
  - India - Geography of Old Silk Road (Box 9, Folder 242)
    "Geographical Problems Concerning the Old Silk Road Region in the Tarim Basin" by Mutsumi Hoyanagi
  - India - Medicine (Box 9, Folder 243)
    "Interviews with Indian Villages re: Health Attitudes" by O. Lewis et al.; "The People's Medicine: Health Care in an Iranian Provincial Town"; "Bauwerke der Nächstenliebe" by Dieter Jetter
  - India - Medicine in India, XVI Century (Box 9, Folder 244)
    "Glimpses into the Practice and Principles of Medicine in Buddhistic India in the 7th Century A.D." by D.V.S. Reddy; "Medicine in India in the Middle of the XVI Century" by D.V.S. Reddy
  - Italy - "Michelangelo and Some of his Biographers" by Francis Haskell (Box 9, Folder 245)
  - Italy - Unfoldered Materials (Box 9, Folder 246)
    "Visita al Museo della Storia dell'dell'Università di Pavia"; "The Antique Instruments at the Museum of History of Science in Florence"; "Italian Doctors and the Royal Society"; "The Color of Dante's Hair" by Robert W. Carrubba
  - Korea - Curran (Box 9, Folder 247)
    "Korean Medical Education" by J.A. Curran and N.L. Gault, Jr.; "Yonsei University Annual Report, 1971-1972"; "Yonsei University Annual Report, 1970-1971"
  - Korea - History of Printing (Box 9, Folder 248)
    "Korea Finds 'Oldest' Printed Text" by Walter Sullivan
  - Korea - "The History of Ancient Korean Medicine" by N.H. Borman, re-edited by Chong-Hwae Kim (Box 9, Folder 249)
  - Korea - Korean Medicine to Japan (Box 9, Folder 250)
    "Seoul Church Monument to Martyred Catholics"; Notes on "Transmission of Korean Medicine to Japan during the Age of the Three Kingdoms by Kim Doo Jong
  - Korea - "Understanding of Science in History of Korea - with Emphasis on Scientists in Early 15th Century" by Jeon Sang-woon (Box 9, Folder 251)
  - Latin America - Brazil History (Box 10, Folder 252)
    "Revista Brasileira de História da Medicina vol. XIII no. 3"; "Fontes para a História da Medicina Brasileira" by Lycurgo de Castro Santos Filho; "Pequena História da Medicina Brasileira" by Lycurgo Santos Filho; "Curiosidades na História Médica Brasileira" by Lycurgo de Castro Santos Filho; "Campinas (Evolução Histórica)" by Lycurgo de Castro Santos Filho; "Médicos de Guaratinguetá no Século XIX (Os Castros Santos – A Santa Casa)" by Lycurgo de Castro Santos Filho
  - Latin America - History of Brazil in the Eighteenth Century (Box 10, Folder 253)
    "Fontes para a História da Medicina Brasileira" by Lycurgo de Castro Santos Filho; "Curiosidades na História Médica Brasileira" by Lycurgo de Castro Santos Filho; "Some Literary Sources for the History of Brazil in the Eighteeenth Century"
  - Latin America - Mexican Phantastica (Box 10, Folder 254)
    "Mexican Phantastica - A Study of the Early Ethnobotanical Sources on Hallucinogenic Drugs" by Francisco Guerra
  - Latin America - "The Development to 1880 of Medical Education in Guatemala" by E. Croft Long (Box 10, Folder 255)
  - Latin America - Aztec Medicine (Box 10, Folder 256)
    "The Chewing of Coca Leaves in Peru" by Vicente Zapata-Ortiz; "Aztec Medicine" by Francisco Guerra; Copies of Pages, "The Naturall and Morall Historie of the East and West Indies"
  - Latin America - "The Influence of High Altitude on Physiology" by Alberto Hurtado (Box 10, Folder 257)
  - Latin America - Mexico (Box 10, Folder 258)
    "La Enseñanza de la Medicine Observacional, Racional, y Cientifica, en Mexico Antecedentes y Perspectivas" by Jose Joaquin Izquierdo; "A Selective List of the Colonial Manuscripts (1564-1800) in the Archives of the Department of Health and Welfare, Mexico City" by Donald B. Cooper
  - Latin America - Latin America Medical Education (Box 10, Folder 259)
    "Medical Education in Latin America, Panamerican Federacion of Associations of Medical Schools
  - The Netherlands - Fourth Pacific Science Congress, Java, 1929, Excursion Guides (Box 10, Folder 260)
    "Cinchona" by C. Spruit P. Pzn; "Coffee Cultivation" by A.J. Ultée; "Fish-Culture" by A.L. Buschkiel; "Rice Cultivation" by A.C. Korenhof; "Rubber" by T.A. Tengwall; "Scientific Institutes" by J. Bernard
  - Philippines - Medical Students in the Philippines (Box 10, Folder 261)
    "University of Santo Tomas, The Faculty of Medicine and Surgery, Announcement, 1962-1963"; Notes on Medical Students in the Philippines; Envelope, Notes on the Philippines
  - Philippines - 4th Congress of the Republic of the Philippines Medical Act of 1959 (Box 10, Folder 262)
    "The Medical Act of 1959"
  - Philippines - Japanese in Philippines (Box 10, Folder 263)
    "Some Notes on the Japanese Community in Manila: 1898-1941" by Serafin D. Quiason
  - Philippines - Colonial Philippines (Box 10, Folder 264)
    "Hospitals and Other Health and Welfare Institutions in Colonial Philippines" by Jose P. Bantug
  - Philippines - Medical Education (Box 10, Folder 265)
    "Essentials and Requirements of an Accredited Medical School"
  - Philippines - Dutch Philippines (Box 10, Folder 266)
    "Dutch Relations with the Philippines, c. 1600-c. 1850. A Survey of Sources in the General State Archives, The Hague, Netherlands" by M.P.H. Roessingh; "Nderlandse Betrekkingen met de Philippijnen, 1600-1800" by M.P.H. Roessingh
  - Spain - Valverde (Box 10, Folder 267)
    "Juan de Valverde de Amusco: Evidence for the Identification of His Portrait - Claimed to be that of Vesalius - with a Reappraisal of His Work" by Francisco Guerra
  - Spain - "Medical Education in Spain" by Antonio Gallego (Box 10, Folder 268)
  - Spain - "Medicine in the Golden Age of Spain" (Box 10, Folder 269)
  - Spain - Unfoldered Materials (Box 10, Folder 270)
    "Paracelsus and his Work in 16th and 17th Century Spain" by José María López Piñero; "Free Spirits of Our West" by Hope Ryden; "Don Carlos of Spain: A Medical Portrait" by C.D. O'Malley; Spain (II): An Understanding with the Americans"
  - Spain - Bibliography of Spanish Medicine (Box 11, Folder 271)
    "Historia Bibliográfica de la Medicina Española" by Don Antonio Hernández Morejón
  - Spain - Medical Colonization of the New World (Box 11, Folder 272)
    "Medical Colonization in the New World" by Francisco Guerra; "The First Hospital in the New World" by Fidelio A. Jimenez; Notes
  - USSR / East Europe - Tigerstedt-Renin-Finn (Box 11, Folder 273)
    "A Proposal" by John C.S. Fray: "Robert Tigerstedt: His Literary and Scientific Achievements"; Correspondence
  - USSR / East Europe - "Some Aspects of American-Rumanian Medical Relations from Columbus until Our Days" by Petrescu Aurel (Box 11, Folder 274)
  - USSR / East Europe - Copernicus (Box 11, Folder 275)
    "Mikołaj Kopernik: Wybitny Przedstawiciel Medycyny XVI Wieku W Polsce 1473-1543" by Mieczysław Skylimowski; Nicholas Copernicus, M.D." by Leonard J. Bruce-Chwatt and Joan M. Bruce-Chwatt; Grant Application, "The Moscow Plague of 1771: A Social History" by John T. Alexander
  - USSR / East Europe - "La Sante Publique et les Personnels de Sante en URSS" (Box 11, Folder 276)
- China, 2.84 Cubic Feet
  This series contains research and reference materials related to Bowers' writings on medicine in China. Files include reprints, articles, notes, and translations.
  - Manchuria - Envelope, References, Naman Igakudo (Box 11, Folder 277)
  - Manchuria - Miscellaneous Papers (Box 11, Folder 278)